Saran .ASoftware Developer

Personal Details



+1513488-3856



Saran1209@gmail.com



8 Sherman Place, Utica, NY - 13502



linkedin.com/in/saranallam



Github.com/saran1209



saran1209.github.io/

Technical Skills

- Python
- SQL
- C
- GIT
- C++
- Flask
- JAVA
- Django
- HTML
- CSS
- Java script

Achievements

- 1st Prize in a Robotics
 Competition Organized by
 Robo Edutech India Pvt.Ltd.
- 1st Prize in a National Level Student Project, Paper and Poster Presentation Competition.
- 3. 3rd Prize in a State level
 Robotics Competition
 Organized by Robo Edutech
 India Pvt.Ltd.
- Volunteered at the 5th
 International conference on "Innovations in Electronics & Communication Engineering (ICIECE-2016)".
- Elected as the Student leader for Robotics lab at GNI institutions.

Professional Summary

Passionate Software Developer with 2+ years of Experience in Python, Java, C++ on IDE — Sublime editor, Jupyter, PyCharm, Visual studio, Eclipse. Well versed with Data structure and algorithms. Experienced in developing Webbased application using Python, Flask and Django Web framework. Experience with several python packages like NumPy, Matplotlib, Beautiful Soup, Pandas data frame.

Experience

SUNY Poly, Utica, NY

(09/2018-05/2020)

Graduate Teaching Assistant

- Assisted Students in Programming (Python & Java)
- Assisted Students in **Object Oriented Programming** course work.
- Supported the class lecture and Presentations of the course work.
- Worked on Research work related to AI and Machine learning.
- Observed Professor in Lecture and best Practices.

Concentrix Daksh Services India

(10/2017-06/2018)

Private Limited.

Transaction Analyst

- Responsible for managing and taking actions according to policy guidelines.
- Supported Team in Policy revision and helped in solving issues.
- Supported Client with mitigating and monitoring user alerts and reports.
- Collaborated with law enforcement officials to track flagged reports.

Bobton IT Solutions Pvt Ltd

(10/2016-09/2017)

Python Developer

- Developed web-based applications using Python, CSS, HTML, Flask, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Prepared and analyzed reports using Python libraries and involved in environment Setup.
- Acquiring, cleaning, and structuring data from multiple sources and maintain databases/data systems.
- Attending and contributing to company development meetings.
- Learning the codebase and improving your coding skills.

Academic Projects

- Developed a Web application using Flask and Implemented Natural Language Processing Chat bot with a Web Scrapper to extract information.
- 2. Heart Disease Prediction using **Machine Learning** algorithms like **KNN**, **Decision Tree**, **Random Forest**.
- 3. Programmed and built a Prototype of a **Steering less vehicle** for **physically Handicapped** person.
- 4. Built and Programmed a Stair climbing robot based on MARS Rover.

Education

SUNY Poly, Utica, NY (2018-2020)

Master of Science in Computer Information Science
GPA – 3.4

GNITC, HYDERABAD, TELANGANA INDIA (2013–2017)

Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering

keywords: Python, Django, Unix, XML, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, MySQL, SQLite, Python Libraries, git, Machine learning, Data Science.